BRIAN STOROE

Email: bstoroe@gmail.com

Phone: 253-326-7454

Web: www.linkedin.com/in/bstoroe

INTRODUCTION

Software engineer with over 10 years of experience. History of working within teams to ensure quality using intuition and automated testing techniques. Motivated to grasp new technologies quickly, and expand testing coverage in breadth and depth. Track record of shipping products that benefit users in a timely manner.

INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

Skytap - Senior Software Design Engineer 2015 - 2019

<u>Skytap</u> is a provider of cloud environments. I transitioned from SDET to SDE roles. Throughout that time, I focused on quality, defect analysis, and comprehensive monitoring of a complex distributed service architecture.

- Shipped customer-facing new/improved features, ensuring high quality and quick turn-around via automated tests. Included billing enhancements, import appliance, and application ACL and tag support.
- Contributed to internal process improvements for data resiliency, security. Included database and server migrations, backup overhaul, and service error/resiliency analysis.
- Developed site and service monitor that were primary discoverer of functional outage and degradation. Implemented in Python and TICK stack on k8s platform.
- Served on-call duty as outage first responder, responsible for initial triage and proper hand-off.
 Setup on-call plan and playbooks during phasing in.

HTC - Senior Software Design Engineer in Test 2011 - 2015

I worked on the following projects as part of <u>HTC</u>'s Creative Labs division, focusing on cloud services, Android development, and innovative user experience.

HTC Vive: As-yet unreleased project

Re-purposed Jira as test case management system.

HTC Zoe: App for photo/video sharing and remixing

- Automated service tests using Java/TestNG/Maven and use JSON schema validation for robust validation.
- Reviewed peer code. Led test iterations, and owned critical services.
- Benchmarked services. Evaluated performance test frameworks and used Chef/AWS to automate test environment.

HTC Backup: First-party backup solution

• Planned and developed testing from the ground up Android app used daily by millions of devices.

- Automated tests using monkeyrunner and uiautomator that was integrated into build pipeline.
- Developed test data generation tools using Android SDK.
- Gained and applied expertise in Android platform–Play Store publishing, logging, SMS/Contacts, backup framework, DDMS, etc.

HTC Hub: First-party asset store for Android

Automated service tests using Java/TestNG/Maven.

Quardev - Software Design Engineer in Test 2005 - 2011

I worked on several projects to support the QA needs of Quardev's clients:

- Disney DCAT Group: Third-Party Commerce System Integration March 2011 September 2011
- Google <u>Omaha</u>: Common Windows Client Installer/Autoupdater September 2007 February 2011
- Microsoft Content Search Platform: AJAX-powered web site and custom server product for indexing and searching exclusive forms of offline content. April 2007 – August 2007
- Microsoft Internet Communications Client: All-in-one package for web, email, photo sharing, and other rich online experiences. March 2006 – March 2007
- Microsoft Product Portal: Web site and comprehensive documentation system for several developer product suites. Testing included a personalized version of the portal as well as publishing tools. October 2005 – February 2006
- Microsoft Developer & IT Courseware: VM-based lab sets for new products and technologies targeted for software developers and system engineers. June 2005 – September 2005
- Radialpoint Internet Security and Privacy Suite: Software providing PC security and online privacy intended for Broadband Service Providers to offer value added services to their customers. April 2005 – May 2005

TESTING SKILLS

- Automated test design and debugging
- Exploratory testing and test design
- Root cause analysis with domain knowledge and available tools
- Producing test cases, targeted status reports, and defect records

TECHNOLOGY SKILLS

Proficient: Python, HTTP, Windows

Intermediate: XML, SOAP, Win32 API

Familiar: C/C++, Linux, Java, C#/.NET, SQL

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Bachelor of Science in Computer Information Systems <u>DeVry University Federal Way</u> Graduated with Honors 2001 - 2004

Microsoft Certified Application Developer (MCAD) 2006